[
  {
    "_id": "q1",
    "question": "What is component life cycle?",
    "answer": "Component life cycle shows the stages of a component's creation to its ultimate destruction."
  },
  {
    "_id": "q2",
    "question": "What is the purpose of life cycles?",
    "answer": "The purpose of life cycles let the developer track and make appropriate changes on the component throughout it's life span"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q3",
    "question": "What are the three stages of a component life cycle?",
    "answer": "Component LIfe Cycle Stages:",
    "list": [
      "Mounting",
      "Updating",
      "Unmounting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q4",
    "question": "What does mounting mean?",
    "answer": "Mounting the stage from component is being constructed until it is fully painted on the DOM"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q5",
    "question": "What does updating mean?",
    "answer": "Updating is the stage where there are changes that needs to be done on the component after it is mounted"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q6",
    "question": "What does unmounting mean?",
    "answer": "Unmounting is the removal of the component From the DOM"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q7",
    "question": "What is the most common built-in mounting lifecycle method?",
    "answer": "`render` is the most common built-in mounting lifecycle method"
  },
  {
    "_id": "q8",
    "question": "What are the mounting life cycle methods?",
    "answer": "Mounting Life Cycle Methods:",
    "list": [
      "`constructor`()",
      "`static getDerivedStateFromProps`(props, state)",
      "`render`()",
      "`componentDidMount`()"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q9",
    "question": "What are the updating life cycle methods?",
    "answer": "Updating Life Cycle Methods:",
    "list": [
      "`static getDerivedStateFromProps`(props, state)",
      "`shouldComponentUpdate`(nextProps, nextState)",
      "`render`()",
      "`getSnapshotBeforeUpdate`(prevProps, prevState)",
      "`componentDidUpdate`(prevProps, prevState, snapshot)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "_id": "q10",
    "question": "What is the unmounting life cycle method?",
    "answer": "Unmounting Method",
    "list": [
      "`componentWillUnmount`()"
    ]
  }
]
